Ilies Reda Merzouk

Full-Stack Developer | Software Engineer

Github | In Linkedin | ⊕ merzouk-ilves.me | ≥ merzouk.ilvase@gmail.com | Rende, Italy

Summary

I'm a software engineer from Algeria, recently graduated from an engineering school. I had the chance to gain a valuable experience working in concrete environments while still being a student. My goal is to continuously learn and grow in my career, as I believe the technology industry offers tremendous growth opportunities. My driving force lies in creating projects with a positive impact on users.

Professional Experience

Feb 2024 - Sep 2024 Data Engineer Rende, Italy

iDEA LAB (Universita Della Calabria)

- Designed and implemented advanced systems based on complex research papers. • Set up and managed Docker infrastructure for seamless integration of Apache Kylin with Apache Superset to enhance data analytics capabilities.
- Contributed to research papers by writing, structuring, conducting complex experiments, and implementing necessary systems for research support.

Mar 2023 - Jul 2023 Research Intern

Lias laboratory (École Nationale Supérieure d'Ingénieurs de Poitiers)

Poitiers, France

- Implementation of an autonomous materialized view management system that improves database performance (PostgreSQL) and energy consumption.
- Developed a neural network prediction model to accurately estimate the execution times of SQL queries.

Full Stack Developer Sep 2022 - Mar 2023

Factory Digitale

Algiers, Algeria

- Contributing to high traffic projects including *temtemone.com*, which has successfully served a user base of over +500,000 users.
- Close collaboration with design and back-end teams on projects such as temtemone.com, medeo-dz.com and factorydigitale.tech, seamlessly integrating React-based components with back-end APIs.

Software Engineer (Intern)

SPE (SONELGAZ Power Company)

Sep 2021 - Oct 2021 Oran, Algeria

EDUCATION

Higher School Of Computer Science (ESI)

Master's (Specialty: Information System and Web)

Higher School Of Computer Science (ESI)

State Engineer (Specialty: Information System and Web)

Sep 2018 - Jul 2023 Sidi Bel Abbès, Algeria

Sep 2018 - Jul 2023 Sidi Bel Abbès, Algeria

SKILLS

- Programming languages: Python, Java, Javascript/HTML/CSS, Typescript, SQL
- Frameworks & libraries: React.js, Next.js, Node.js, Express.js, Redux, Tailwind
- Tools: Git, Linux, Docker, PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQL Server, MongoDB, FireBase
- Languages: English (Fluent) | French (Professional) | Arabic (Native)